<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Preparedness and Response</title>
    <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 16:12:36 -0000</pubDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenges, Commitments at Central and East Africa’s One Health Conference</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/challenges-commitments-at-central-and-east-africas-one-health-conference</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/challenges-commitments-at-central-and-east-africas-one-health-conference</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Musenero, now Assistant Commissioner of Epidemiology and Surveillance for the Ministry of Health in Uganda, was at the forefront of the global H5N1 pandemic crisis. She had recently been recruited as project manager of USAID’s H5N1 response program, and was tasked with pulling together a team of specialists to respond to it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/small.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;small&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I decided we needed everyone at the table – veterinarians, wildlife specialists, biologists, zoologists, entymologists, everyone,” said Dr. Musenero in describing the challenges the program faced. “USAID had used a multi-disciplinary response in other countries, and it had been successful.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a relatively low incidence of H5N1 in Uganda, the program’s task force used their lessons learned from H5N1 preparedness to focus on other zoonotic disease threats, including yersinia pestis – a disease better known as the plague. Together, the task force designed inexpensive, easy-to-implement programs focused on prevention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 2007, in a year, deaths from yersinia pestis in Uganda dropped from almost seven thousand to almost none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following her experience on the project, Dr. Musenero became an evangelist for the One Health approach - a collaborative, multi-disciplinary approach used to address health challenges from zoonotic diseases, like H5N1 and other pandemic threats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stories just like Dr. Musenero’s have brought hundreds of global health leaders in Africa to meet for their second annual conference in Kampala on Monday, November 16. The conference, organized by the One Health Central and East Africa association (OHCEA), is designed to share best practices for the One Health approach among global health, medicine, veterinary, environment and other technical professionals, as well as officials and policymakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the heart of the conference is the question - in every country, health programs and approaches are competing for limited resources. How can the technical professionals best promote the One Health approach to leaders and policymakers?
“We know the approach works, because we’ve used it successfully in the field,” said Dr. Musenero. “I’ve made the analogy – One Health is like our girlfriend. It’s time to make it our wife. We need to make it legal and permanent.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of building an effective and sustainable approach to One Health at a national level was exactly the focus of Wednesday’s conference panel, hosted by USAID’s Preparedness &amp;amp; Response (P&amp;amp;R) project. The panel brought together six One Health leaders from five Central and East African countries, including Dr. Musenero, to share the challenges and lessons learned of the One Health platforms in their country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The panel’s keynote address was given by the Honorable Dr. Rwamirama Brith, Minister of Agriculture, Animal Industries and Fisheries in Rwanda, who emphasized the importance of regional and international cooperation in response to emerging pandemic threats. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are ready to learn from, and work with, our neighbors, because these threats are transboundary in nature,” said the Honorable Dr. Brith in his closing remarks. “Just as no one sector can address these diseases on their own, no one country can.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senator Monique Ouli Ndongo, a One Health champion in Cameroon who helped develop a platform widely recognized as one of the most comprehensive in Africa, presented on the structure of the secretariat in her country. She was followed by Dr. Kariuki Njenga, founder of the technical coordinating body the Zoonotic Disease Unit (ZDU) in Kenya, who highlighted the contrast between the two countries’ approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One Health platforms cannot be a ‘one size fits all’ approach,” said Lisa Kramer, USAID Regional Advisor of the Emerging Pandemic Threats program and panel moderator. “Each platform has its advantages and disadvantages, and it’s important to share that information.”
Their presentations were followed by Dr. Musenero, who spoke movingly about both her experiences as a One Health advocate in Uganda and her service as an epidemiologist in Sierra Leone on the front line of the 2014 Ebola outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Professionally, we were caught off-guard,” said Dr. Musenero of the outbreak. “The level of competence at both the national and international level has been tested, and found wanting…we needed more expertise on the ground.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Musenero was followed by Dr. Robinson Mdegela, who outlined the One Health strategy being developed in Tanzania. Panelists also responded to questions from the 50+ high-level One Health experts from across Africa attending the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All participants emphasized the need for coordination in establishing a One Health approach in their country. Many had worked with USAID’s P&amp;amp;R project directly to further develop a platform for the approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We know that you can have the best research, the best training, the best systems at the university level,” said Serge Nzietcheung, the P&amp;amp;R project’s Deputy Director in Africa during the panel’s opening remarks. “But if you don’t have the government capacity, structure, policies and laws to support their work, the One Health approach won’t be effective.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P&amp;amp;R, with PREDICT and One Health Workforce, is part of the suite of projects under the second phase of USAID’s Emerging Pandemic Threats (EPT-2) program. The mandate of the P&amp;amp;R project is to establish or strengthen One Health platforms in 21 target countries across Africa and Asia. P&amp;amp;R accomplishes that mandate both by facilitating opportunities, such as this panel, for technical professionals, leaders and policymakers to share information. The project also provides direct consultation to country governments on issues such as One Health organizational development, institutional capacity building, and policy advocacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The P&amp;amp;R project has been extraordinarily helpful in developing the platform in Cameroon,” said Senator Ndongo, on her experience working with the project. “Their technical expertise has given us the background to shape a lot of decisions.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward, a lack of technical expertise in government remains an obstacle for a comprehensive, multi-disciplinary response to emerging pandemic threats. One of the most frequent challenges encountered was simply a lack of commitment at the leadership level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a challenge to approach health officials in the government – people who are dealing with HIV, malaria, tuberculosis – and convince them that zoonotic diseases should be a priority, because there might be an outbreak at some point in the future,” said Dr. Njenga, talking about some of the obstacles he had faced. “But in 2014, we were confronted with that future directly.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P&amp;R Project Hosts International Government Representatives for One Health Workshop</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/one-health-workshop</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 13:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/one-health-workshop</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)-funded Preparedness and Response (P&amp;amp;R) project brought together 30 representatives from 10 countries to learn what the project and its partners are doing to build national and regional One Health capacity to emerging and re-emerging zoonotic diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/jerry_meeting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;jerry_meeting&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One Health seeks to integrate multiple disciplines working locally, nationally, and globally to attain optimal health for people, animals, and the environment. Participants represented their countries’ various ministries of human health, environment, and animal health—the three pillars of the One Health approach. P&amp;amp;R has a dual mandate to help countries design and implement national preparedness and response plans for public health events of unknown etiology and to establish and strengthen National One Health Platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two-day conference featured 10 speakers and maximum time for networking and sharing lessons learned. The USAID Predict 2 project—which works to shift the prevention and surveillance of disease outbreaks towards identification and mitigation of viral spillover—and the USAID One Health Workforce—which supports One Health university networks to participate with government and other key partners in defining one health workforce needs—also presented to participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conference participants benefitted most from the shared experiences. “We are going to go back home and try to address the issues of One Health in a holistic approach,” said Janneth Mghamba of Tanzania’s Ministry of Health and Human Welfare. “Rather than working in silos, all the sectors need to work together.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another participant stressed the importance of each sector trusting the other. “In Thailand, we have two key words: talk and trust. After meetings of the three sectors, we need to talk and discuss like friends. And because each of our organizations have different cultures, we need to be able to trust each other and act upon information shared,” said Soawapak Hinjoy of Thailand’s Bureau of Epidemiology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The USAID P&amp;amp;R project is one component of the Emerging Pandemic Threats (EPT 2) program. EPT2 has three overarching purposes: the prevention of the spillover, amplification, and spread of new and re-emerging zoonotic viruses; early detection of new viruses when they emerge; and their timely and effective control. EPT2 is part of the Obama Administration’s Global Health Security Agenda, which brings together U.S. government agencies and other national governments to address natural and manmade disease threats worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of the workshop, participants articulated their specific country needs that the P&amp;amp;R team plans to address. “This workshop has been invaluable to the P&amp;amp;R team as we begin to launch activities in more than 20 countries in Southeast Asia and Africa,” said Chief of Party Jerry Martin. “The Ebola outbreak demonstrates the enormous human and economic costs that pandemic threats can inflict in the absence of strong preparedness and response systems. P&amp;amp;R is focused on helping these countries address these gaps in a sustainable and effective manner.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
