<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Preparedness and Response</title>
    <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 03:28:39 -0000</pubDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Health Policy Modeling in Ethiopia</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/one-health-policy-modeling-in-ethiopia</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 03:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/one-health-policy-modeling-in-ethiopia</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following a request from the Ethiopian Ministry of Agriculture and Fisheries, P&amp;amp;R project developed an Interactive One Health (OH) policy modeling tool, believed to generate useful information related to disease of interest that may arise as a result of massive livestock intensification planned under the Livestock Master Plan and the Growth and Transformation Plan II of the country. The developed One Health interactive tool was presented to Government of Ethiopia (GoE) partners, preceded by a hands-on training conducted on the use of the tool. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The One Health policy modeling tool incorporates some of the comments and suggestions gathered during its presentation to GoE staff in summer 2016. This includes Greenhouse gas emission, Water footprint of livestock production on availability of water, Economic loss in Animals and the Disability-Adjusted Life Year (DALY) in human beings as a result of zoonotic diseases. The tool enables users to compare the impact of different intervention on disease prevalence both in animals and human beings, including other economic and environmental variables.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the tool can be applied for any disease of interest with little adaptation, inputs related to Brucellosis in cattle were used to show its impact both in cattle and human beings over a ten year period of forecast. However, one of the challenges faced in using the tool is due to lack of relevant and appropriate data, such as disease prevalence both in animals and humans.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a next step, it was agreed that additional efforts should be made to further refine the tool, search for literature and other sources, and collect appropriate data on Brucellosis. A committee of four representatives, two each from Ministry of Livestock and Fisheries and Ministry of Health were selected to work on using the tool and specifically gather available data on Brucellosis and eventually produce a report, under P&amp;amp;R’s technical support, coordination and guidance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two day training workshop attracted a total of 17 representatives from the Ministry of Livestock and Fisheries; Ministry of Health/Ethiopian Public Health Institute; Ethiopian Wildlife Authority; FAO, USAID and CDC, which greatly contributed to further refinement of the tool. The workshop was officially opened by Dr. Thomas Chernet, Policy advisor to the Minister of Livestock and Fisheries. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Government Partners Commit to Collaboration for Health Security in Indonesia</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/key-government-partners-commit-to-collaboration-for-health-security-in-indonesia</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/key-government-partners-commit-to-collaboration-for-health-security-in-indonesia</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On March 16, 2017, five government ministries in Indonesia affirmed their commitment to a One Health approach to address health security threats and outlined areas for joint action at a One Health Seminar held in Jakarta. The event, organized by FAO and supported by USAID, convened high-level officials and representatives from the Ministry of Health, Ministry of Agriculture, Ministry of Environment and Forestry, Ministry of Marine Affairs and Fisheries, and Coordinating Ministry of Human Development and Culture with the objective of advancing a multilateral, multisectoral One Health approach to the prevention, detection, and response to threats to human and animal health, such as highly pathogenic infectious diseases or anti-microbial resistance (AMR). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 2014, Indonesia has been a member of the Global Health Security Agenda and in 2016, a lead country on the GHSA zoonotic disease action package with Vietnam. In his opening remarks, Hon. Hari Priyono, Secretary General of the Ministry of Agriculture, emphasized the country&amp;rsquo;s commitment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Global health security is a shared responsibility that cannot be achieved by a single actor or sector of government,&amp;rdquo; said the Secretary General. &amp;ldquo;Its success depends upon collaboration among the health, security, environment and agriculture sectors, using a One Health approach.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seminar had a thematic focus on the threat posed by anti-microbial resistance (AMR) to public health, food security, and development progress overall – a prime example of a global health issue that cannot be solved by a single sector alone. Presenters and panel discussions raised the opportunities and promise of One Health as a holistic approach, but also noted the practical challenges of improving coordination and information sharing between the human health, animal health and environmental sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Brian McFeeters, Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy to Indonesia, underscored the need for “formal and informal mechanisms and structures for making and implementing decisions [on health security], which takes effort and time.” Dr. Naahli Kelsum, Assistant Deputy for Diseases Prevention and Response from the Coordinating Ministry of Human Development and Culture, highlighted ongoing efforts by the Ministry and other government stakeholders, and supported by USAID Preparedness and Response (P&amp;amp;R) project, to institutionalize One Health and sustain multisectoral stakeholder collaboration for short- and long-term public health and food security. Dr. Naahli called all seminar participants to action. “[One Health] is not just a concept – now we need to implement.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key stakeholders further affirmed their commitment to greater collaboration for health security in the issuance of a joint communique to media outlets and the general public, entitled, “Implementation of the One Health Approach in Indonesia with special emphasis on Antimicrobial Resistance (AMR).” This joint communique and One Health Seminar generated significant coverage by local news outlets including the Jakarta Globe, Kompas, and Antara News.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Multisectoral Collaboration for Disease Surveillance, Investigation, and Response in Rwanda</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/multisectoral-collaboration-with-existinginstitutional-frameworks</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 18:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/multisectoral-collaboration-with-existinginstitutional-frameworks</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2014, the government of Rwanda adopted a 2014 - 2018 One Health Strategic Plan that reflects a shared commitment to enhance collaboration between environmental, animal, and human health sectors to address complex health challenges. Better collaboration leads to strengthened surveillance, early detection, rapid response, prevention, and control of zoonotic disease and other infectious disease threats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, until now, not all these sectors were aware of how key technical and institutional frameworks for the country&amp;rsquo;s health system operated under the International Health Regulations (IHR) and the Terrestrial Animal Health Code (TAHC). For sustainable multisectorial collaboration and coordination, each sector needed a better understanding of their partners&amp;#39; role disease surveillance, outbreak investigation, and response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address this challenge, the Rwanda One Health Steering Committee, with technical assistance from P&amp;amp;R, organized and conducted a workshop on institutional frameworks and collaboration mechanisms in disease surveillance, outbreak investigation and response, held in Kigali on February 21 - 22, 2017. This exercise helped to build a foundation for multisectoral collaboration on prevention, detection, and response to infectious disease among the sectors. A total of 23 representatives from different institutions of One Health collaboration - ministries, directorates, research and academic institutions, the World Health Organization (WHO), the FAO country office, and Rwanda OIE delegate took part in the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specific outcomes included: 1) sharing institutional and technical frameworks of each of the ministries in dealing with disease surveillance, reporting, outbreak investigation, and response; 2) building awareness regarding WHO, FAO and OIE regulatory standards and code; 3) identifying areas, mechanisms and tools for multisectoral collaboration; and 4), developing a road map for the adoption of a multisectoral institutional framework for prevention, detection and response of zoonotic diseases and other public health threats - with adopting the framework as the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responding to threat of Highly Pathogenic Avian Influenza in East Africa</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/the-threat-of-highly-pathogenic-avian-influenza-in-east-africa</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/the-threat-of-highly-pathogenic-avian-influenza-in-east-africa</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On January 2, 2017, numerous dead wild birds were discovered on Uganda’s Lutembe Bay on Lake Victoria. These birds, and others including ducks and chickens identified in the Masaka District on January 13, 2017, tested positive for H5N8, one of the many subtypes of highly pathogenic avian influenza (HPAI) found worldwide but detected for the first time in the East Africa subregion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outbreak of HPAI in Uganda raises concerns because the country has a combination of factors that could contribute to further spread of the disease, including: a population of over forty million domestic poultry; a combination of a variety of informal trade of domestic poultry within the region, the presence of the disease in an area considered seasonal shelter of migratory birds that are reservoir of AI virus; the existence of numerous live bird markets; and a large number of backyard poultry producers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response, the Government of Uganda and other East African countries and their partners, including the USAID Emerging Pandemic Threats 2 (EPT-2) program partners (e.g; FAO, PREDICT-2, One Health Workforce, and P&amp;amp;R)  are stepping up preparedness and response efforts to reduce the spread of H5N8 and prevent it from becoming an endemic disease within the subregion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Government of Uganda activated the National Task Force (NTF) to manage its response, in coordination with the country’s recently established National One Health Platform’s secretariat, the Zoonotic Disease Coordination Office (ZDCO). The ZDCO provided technical guidance to the NTF on developing HPAI H5N8 outbreak response activities. Specifically, with the NTF, the ZDCO reviewed the draft Joint Emergency Response plan and budget; drafted a joint Cabinet Memorandum and press releases; and reviewed and updated existing Avian Influenza Communication Strategy documents and IEC materials in English and local languages in liaison with the Communications Subcommittee. P&amp;amp;R provided technical support to ZDCO throughout the outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, P&amp;amp;R Regional  and National One Health Technical Advisors are  also supporting preparedness and response actions in neighboring countries across East Africa. The Rwanda One Health Steering Committee has convened meetings with One Health stakeholders in the government, EPT-2 partners, local leaders, selected border posts, and national response teams in selected districts. The multi-sectoral team developed HPAI awareness messages to spread the word about the ongoing in-country preparedness, reporting channels, emergency contact numbers (in case of an outbreak or any detected sick or dead birds), and sensitization of communities and local leaders after identifying sites to enhance surveillance. One Health stakeholders are also currently reviewing the 2006 Avian Influenza Preparedness and Response Plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Kenya, the Zoonotic Disease Unit (ZDU) convened a national influenza taskforce meeting, bringing together One Health sector ministries, non-governmental and private sectors, and partners including FAO, WHO, OIE, WSU, ILRI, and PREDICT-2. As a result, the national influenza task force committees undertook rapid risk assessment, surveillance, and communication, as well as activated laboratory capabilities, resource mobilization, and coordination, in line with the Kenya Influenza Contingency Plan. P&amp;amp;R continues to provide technical assistance to the ZDU and multi-sectoral response efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Ethiopia, P&amp;amp;R consulted with various stakeholders, including members of the National One Health Steering Committee, Ethiopian Wildlife Authority, National Animal Health Diagnostic and Investigation Center, Epidemiology Directorate of the Ministry of Livestock and Fisheries, EPT-2 partners, and FAO, to raise awareness and stimulate the initiation of preparedness actions While heightened surveillance has found no reported cases of HPAI, the Ethiopian Wildlife Authority has increased the monitoring of wetland wild bird activity in potential hot spots. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Tanzania, the One Health Coordination Unit (OHCU) established last year in the Prime Minister’s Office is coordinating preparedness and response actions. This coordination has improved multi-sectoral field monitoring of poultry and wild birds conducted by public health, wildlife, and veterinary services. Regular updates are being shared among stakeholders and emergency readiness exercises/simulations are ongoing. The OHCU has convened key sectors to develop a three-month HPAI contingency plan, which has been submitted to the cabinet of ministers for approval.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning Before the Next Outbreak in Indonesia</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/planning-for-coordination-before-an-outbreak-in-indonesia</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/planning-for-coordination-before-an-outbreak-in-indonesia</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From Jan. 25 – 27, over 80 district and provincial animal and human health, disaster agency, development and  planning agency, as well as police officials conducted a simulation exercise in Pontianak, West Kalimantan, to pilot One Health Coordination Guidelines in a non-emergency, or pre-outbreak, situation. Over the past six months, P&amp;amp;R has been supporting the Coordinating Ministry for Human Development and Cultural Affairs (PMK-Komnas Zoonosis), in collaboration with FAO, to develop OH Coordination Guidelines to strengthen the provincial multi-sectoral coordination mechanism in both emergency and pre-outbreak situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An earlier pilot of the Coordination Guidelines in an emergency situation was conducted with 30 provincial and district officials from December 19 - 21, 2016 in Pekanbaru, Riau.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[This roll-out of the One Health Coordination Guidelines] is intended to highlight how critical rapid, accurate and effective coordinated action is,&amp;rdquo; said Dr. Naalih Kelsum, MPH, Assistant Deputy for Diseases Prevention and Respond, Ministry of Human Development and Cultural Affairs, during his opening remarks. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s critical for the prevention and response in the emergency pandemic situation - both at national and sub-national levels.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing on the lessons learned from these two pilots, the OH Coordination Guidelines will be finalized and presented for governmental endorsement for nationwide implementation by mid-2017. Following governmental endorsement, P&amp;amp;R will work with key One Health stakeholders in country to expand implementation of these guidelines among animal health, human health and environmental officials, at the national level and across Indonesia’s 34 provinces. Standardized and sustained effective coordination and communications mechanisms are key for not only responding to, but also preventing, future outbreaks of recurring or emerging infectious diseases that negatively impact human health and livelihoods.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responding to Avian Influenza in Bangladesh</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/responding-to-avian-influenza-in-bangladesh</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 18:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/responding-to-avian-influenza-in-bangladesh</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Jan 15, a poultry die-off was observed on a poultry farm in Dhamrai subdistrict near Dhaka, Bangladesh, and reported by local farmers to the Department of Livestock Services.  An investigation confirmed 732 deaths among a flock of 3000 chickens and lab testing confirmed contamination with H5N1 virus, a subtype of highly pathogenic avian influenza (HPAI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, samples from dead house crows found at the Rajshahi Medical College and Dhaka Medical College initially confirmed positive for H5N1 using a Rapid Antigen Detection test (RAT). Bangladesh had not reported any official outbreak of HPAI in poultry since 2014.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To its credit, and thanks to the support of the EPT-2 partners, the Government of Bangladesh responded quickly. On Jan 18, a meeting of the National Technical Committee (Livestock Sector) was convened by the Department of Livestock Services (DLS) to review the outbreak situation. Chaired by the Director General of DLS, the meeting included participants from the Ministry of Health and Family Welfare (Directorate General of Health Services), Bangladesh Forest Department, Bangladesh Agricultural University, ICDDR/B, FAO, P&amp;amp;R, and other partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With partners, the government noted that while the numbers in the outbreaks were comparatively low, other recent surveillance data has reflected the continuous circulation of HPAI in Bangladesh. A recent study by FAO collected samples from arrival, slaughter, and exposure areas from 104 live bird markets in Dhaka, and found that 90 turned initial positive indicators for HPAI.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has concluded that HPAI is endemic in the country, and began to plan for both eradication and prevention of spillover. They called for a new vaccination policy and an updating of the AI preparedness and response plan, beginning with a specific plan for cleaning and disinfection of the live bird markets. P&amp;amp;R will continue to support outbreak response and the government’s efforts as they evolve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating an Anthrax Outbreak in Tanzania</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/investigating-an-anthrax-outbreak-in-tanzania</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 08:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/investigating-an-anthrax-outbreak-in-tanzania</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following a request from the Government of Tanzania through the Ministry of Health, Community Development, Gender, Children and Elderly, P&amp;amp;R provided technical support, coordination and facilitation of a multi-sectoral investigation of an Anthrax outbreak in Arusha, Tanzania.  Anthrax is one of the key zoonotic diseases for which cross-sectoral collaboration among animal, human and environmental health sectors is both feasible and essential for effective prevention and control. P&amp;amp;R&amp;rsquo;s technical support was designed to facilitate the nascent One Health Coordination Unit (OHCU) to lead multi-sectoral coordination exercises. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P&amp;amp;R focused on providing technical advice in the outbreak management approach, facilitating planning meetings, supporting travel to the field, facilitating documentation of how the district, region and nation were prepared for the outbreak. Human, animal and environmental health experts jointly planned, carried out field investigations and made recommendations to the national taskforce cutting across all One Health sectors. Cross border districts representatives from Kenya were engaged in this process on how to stop the disease from spreading across the border, with financial assistance from the World Bank.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This collaborative effort provided first-hand experience to the OHCU on the significance of effective preparedness and response mechanisms. The outbreak investigation identified salient risk factors, impacts and potential interventions for the development of a long term prevention and control strategy for the country.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Ebola Virus Disease Preparedness and Response Plans in Liberia</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/updating-ebola-virus-disease-preparedness-and-response-plans-in-liberia</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 08:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/updating-ebola-virus-disease-preparedness-and-response-plans-in-liberia</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Frequently, emerging pandemic threats begin as local public health events (PHE). A PHE is an occurence that results in serious illness, has the capacity to spread, and requires a coordinated response. Without a coordinated response, critical delays occur in detection, reporting, investigation, and testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the 2014 Ebola outbreak, Liberia has worked closely with partner organizations like P&amp;amp;R to update their existing Ebola-specific preparedness and response plans to better respond to future public health events of an initially unknown etiology. The World Health Organization&amp;rsquo;s (WHO) PHE framework serves as a concise technical and managerial guiding document for multi-sectoral preparedness and response to public health events. P&amp;amp;R uses the framework as a tool to help countries understand where they have capacity gaps, while also showing them the value of a coordinated One Health approach to outbreak preparedness and response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This December, the P&amp;amp;R national One Health advisor in Liberia (NOHTSA) provided technical expertise in the design and development of a Liberian Ministry of Internal Affairs (MIA)-organized workshop, funded by the United Nations Mission in Liberia (UNMIL), to upgrade existing Ebola virus disease preparedness and response plans. The upgrades included expanding them into multi-hazard plans and better integrating multi-sector One Health coordination and communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The P&amp;amp;R NOHTA presented and served as a co-facilitator, alongside experts from the Armed Forces of Liberia and UNMIL. More than 80 representatives from 15 counties participated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting the Agenda for Global Health Security in Lao PDR</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/setting-the-agenda-for-global-health-security-in-lao</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 08:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/setting-the-agenda-for-global-health-security-in-lao</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of USAID&amp;rsquo;s support for the US Global Health Security Agenda (GHSA), P&amp;amp;R is providing ongoing technical assistance in the development and implementation of the National GHSA Roadmap - which sets key targets for 2021 across different action packages, including countering antimicrobial resistance, strengthening surveillance, establishing emergency operations centers, expanding a skilled global health security workforce, and building a whole-of-government approach to biosafety and biosecurity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lao PDR currently faces many high-risk disease threats, including cross-border infectious and emerging diseases that can pass from animals to humans, particularly during periods of development and environmental stress. The complex nature of these health threats requires infrastructure, equipment, a skilled workforce, and coordination among government agencies, the private sector, and civil society in order to respond effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On December 21-22, P&amp;amp;R facilitated a two-day workshop, convening over 120 representatives from government agencies and international organizations, to assist the Lao government in the formation and implementation of its National Five-Year Global Health Security Roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We congratulate Laos on its longstanding leadership in preparedness for emerging disease threats,&amp;rdquo; said USAID Laos Country Office Director Alexandria Huerta, &amp;ldquo;and for working across sectors to develop the GHSA Roadmap.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The immediate next step before the plan goes into effect is to seek governmental endorsement by the Ministries of Health, Agriculture, and Forestry, anticipated to take place in early 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a One Health Framework in West Africa</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/building-a-one-health-framework-in-west-africa</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 23:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/building-a-one-health-framework-in-west-africa</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In November 2016, USAID co-sponsored One Health Technical and Ministerial Meetings in Dakar, with the West African Health Organization (WAHO) arm of the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS), the World Health Organization (WHO), the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), the U.N. Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO), and the World Organization of Animal Health (OIE). The goal of the workshop was to foster the institutionalization and the ownership of the One Health approach in all participating West African countries to improve regional prevention, detection and response to emerging infectious diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the preparation for the Dakar meetings, P&amp;amp;R country national One Health Advisors worked with WHO, FAO, OIE and CDC to share One Health information, provide additional guidance, and work with country delegates from different ministries to meet and jointly prepare their participation as a country team. In Guinea, P&amp;amp;R organized, with the WHO, a joint pre-meeting workshop to share with members of the delegation the objectives of the approach in the country. In Mali, P&amp;amp;R responded to government and USAID requests for P&amp;amp;R to support the revision and update of the national zoonotic disease policy and plan, and facilitated a stakeholders’ orientation and consultative workshop in which members of Mali delegation participated and contributed to the development of a consensus on a national One Health framework and an operational plan for its implementation. In Cote d’Ivoire, P&amp;amp;R identified participants from stakeholder ministries, and helped define the country’s multisectoral progress made toward establishing a GHSA and One Health coordination platform. In Sierra Leone and Liberia, P&amp;amp;R developed briefing presentations for the delegations on One Health for each of the breakout sessions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to the Dakar meeting, P&amp;amp;R has also worked with WAHO on supporting ECOWAS in strengthening national and regional mechanisms for surveillance, early warning, preparedness and response to epidemics. WAHO, as one of the main components of the new ECOWAS Regional Centre for Disease Surveillance and Control, had decided to establish an ECOWAS Regional Rapid Response Team (ERRRT), with P&amp;amp;R providing important technical and facilitation support to organize an ERRRT Team Building Workshop. More than 100 delegates from 15 countries and partner organizations, including CDC, WHO, FAO, OIE, and the African Union reviewed and developed a consensus on the ERRRT composition, terms of references (TOR), standard operating procedures (SOPs), and resources needed during pre-deployment, deployment and recovery phases. P&amp;amp;R also designed and facilitated a tabletop simulation exercise on regional cross-border response to a zoonotic disease outbreak, providing guidance on ways to integrate the One Health approach throughout the process. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the success of the ERRRT development and the November technical and ministerial meetings, P&amp;amp;R will continue to provide guidance to WAHO as it develops the ECOWAS One Health implementation framework – and support individual countries in implementing the action plan – to build a truly regional multisectoral mechanism for West Africa in the prevention, detection and response to a public health event.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Grassroots Movement to Government Priority - One Health in Bangladesh</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/from-grassroots-movement-to-government-priority-one-health-in-bangladesh</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 22:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/from-grassroots-movement-to-government-priority-one-health-in-bangladesh</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In population-dense Bangladesh, infectious diseases that can be transmitted between animals and humans, such as avian influenza, pose a serious public health threat. Environmental stress and a rapidly expanding livestock industry compound the threat, putting people’s health and livelihoods at risk.As in many countries, officials and technical experts involved in addressing disease outbreaks are dispersed across human, veterinary, agriculture, environment and wildlife health sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recognizing the need for multidisciplinary collaboration across these sectors is fundamental to the “One Health” approach to controlling outbreaks of diseases such as avian influenza or new pathogens that may not be known. For these reasons, the USAID-funded Preparedness and Response (P&amp;amp;R) project is working with FAO and the Government of Bangladesh to advance the country’s emergent One Health movement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2008, One Health Bangladesh was a response to the country’s first outbreak of avian influenza the year prior. The effort involved several consultations among stakeholders from government, non-governmental organizations, academia and civil society. In 2012, One Health Bangladesh developed a Strategic Framework for One Health that was, over the next three years, endorsed by the Ministry of Health, the Ministry of Fisheries and Livestock, and the Ministry of Environment and Forestry. With governmental endorsement, the goal now is to institutionalize One Health in Bangladesh by building a mechanism or “platform” to support effective coordination and information sharing across human, animal, and environmental health sectors. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April 2016, USAID P&amp;amp;R, One Health Bangladesh, and the Institute of Epidemiology, Disease Control and Research brought together representatives from government agencies in health, livestock and environment; World Health Organization; Food and Agriculture Organization; U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; and other partners to create a roadmap for institutionalizing One Health. Just two months later, a formal decision was made to establish a One Health Secretariat and Steering Committee. To be formally adopted by the Government of Bangladesh is a remarkable milestone and affirmation of One Health in Bangladesh, from its humble beginning as a voluntary movement in 2008. Following this decision, in September, USAID P&amp;amp;R and FAO convened 60 One Health champions and stakeholders in Dhaka to draft Terms of Reference for the One Health Secretariat and Steering Committee. This meeting marks an important milestone toward achieving a proactive, sustained approach to pressing health challenges. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next steps include finalizing the Terms of Reference and identifying resources to support the One Health Secretariat. USAID will continue its support for a strong and sustainable One Health mechanism in Bangladesh that promotes dynamic and effective collaboration. To be certain, cross-sectoral coordination for preventive action and efficient response to disease outbreaks can make all the difference when lives and livelihoods are on the line.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with the Private Sector in Cameroon</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/working-with-the-private-sector-in-cameroon</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 22:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/working-with-the-private-sector-in-cameroon</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cameroon&amp;rsquo;s National Program for the Prevention and Fight against Emerging and Re-emerging Zoonotic Diseases (NPPFERZD) is using the Africa Women Cup of Nations, with its final on Saturday, as a catalytic event to strengthen public-private collaboration on preparedness and response to public health threats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A large-scale international gathering like the football tournament has the potential to spread disease rapidly across borders, so having a prevention plan in place is essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July 2016, the NPPFERZD facilitated a private-public forum on coordination of preparedness and response plans in advance of the Africa Women Cup of Nations. 
Cameroon’s main private sector association, The Cameroon Inter-Professional Business Group (GICAM), participated in the forum, as did the Cameroon National Oil Transformation (SONARA), Exxon Mobil-Cameroon Oil Transport Company (COTCO), Oil and Gas Production Company (PERENCO), and Electricity of Cameroon Company (ENEO). They were joined by government ministries including Public Health; Forestry and Wildlife; Environment, Natural Conservation, and Sustainable Development; Livestock, Fisheries, and Animal Industries; and Communication together with the Territorial Administration and the Police. The USAID-funded One Health Workforce and PREDICT-2 projects, and the University of Montagne, a member of the One Health Central and East Africa (OCHEA) network, also participated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The forum has contributed to identification and streamlining of joint activities between the public and private sectors. Following the forum, in September 2016, P&amp;amp;R provided expert assistance to the NPPFERZD ’s technical committee during a four-day assessment of preparedness and response conducted in the towns of Douala and Limbe, the location for the selected stadiums for the upcoming Africa Women Cup of Nations. Specific preparedness and response plan gaps were identified. In October 2016, a joint public-private sector tabletop simulation exercise was conducted to test the plan, with an Ebola virus disease outbreak used as a possible scenario.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This assessment was imperative given that the Africa Women Cup of Nations will not only generate massive movements of groups of people and traffic of goods, but also constitutes major public health risks. The biennial international football championship tournament will provide a great opportunity to P&amp;amp;R and the NPPFERZD  ’s technical committee to advocate for the adoption of a multi-sectoral approach to address public health challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uganda One Health Day Launch</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/uganda-one-health-day-launch</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 13:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/uganda-one-health-day-launch</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On November 3, 2016, during the first ever Global One Health day, the government of Uganda in collaboration with the U.S. Government officially launched a National One Health Platform to formalize collaboration among four key government sectors (the Ministry of Agriculture, Animal Industry and Fisheries; Ministry of Health; Ministry of Water and Environment and Uganda Wildlife Authority) in the implementation of the One Health Approach - a proactive, innovative strategy to prevent, detect and respond to existing and emerging pandemic threats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The launch was presided over by the Rt. Hon. Prime Minister who was represented by the Hon. Minister of Health, Dr Jane Ruth Aceng. The occasion was also graced by the State Minister for Animal Industries, Hon. Joy Kabatsi, the U.S. Ambassador to Uganda, H.E. Deborah R. Malac and senior level government officials from collaborating ministries including; the Ministry of Agriculture, Animal Industry and Fisheries; Ministry of Health; Ministry of Water and Environment; Uganda Wildlife Authority and Office of the Prime Minister. Other key partners present included, USAID, CDC, Walter-Reed, FAO, WHO, P&amp;amp;R, OHCEA, PREDICT 2, AFENET, academic and professional associations. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his speech, the Prime Minister stated “The launch of the platform marks a major milestone for the country in our efforts to meet our national and international obligations, regarding management of existing and emerging zoonotic diseases as well as other threats that require multisectoral approach such as antimicrobial resistance”.  He pledged that Uganda government will continue to support the GHSA roadmap and will be the first African country to host the forthcoming GHSA Conference scheduled for September 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Ambassador Malac&amp;rsquo;s remarks, she said, &amp;ldquo;As one of the original signatory countries and an active participant in the Global Health Security Agenda, Uganda has done important work in protecting the health of not only Ugandans, but of people all over the world. With the One Health platform, Uganda will be able to better address the serious health challenges that can impact the stability and security of people across the globe”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ensure sustainability, the platform will be legally anchored within a government institution such as the National Institute for Public Health, which is being established. The launch of the platform, the signing of the institutional collaboration framework and the MOU between sectors, and the appointment of individuals to the OHTWG and ZDCO marks the completion of the initial process towards the establishment of a One Health platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thailand One Health Day Conference</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/thailand-one-health-day-2016</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/thailand-one-health-day-2016</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;P&amp;amp;R has organized the Thailand One Health Day Conference 2016, an opportunity to share information and exchange best practices among Thailand One Health leaders and practitioners. The conference is being co-convened with the eight organizations party to the One Health MOU in Thailand. The purpose is both learning- and advocacy-oriented. Additionally, participants will plan for the expansion of One Health at the provincial level in Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P&amp;amp;R Asia Regional Director Dr. Pasakorn Akarasewi will facilitate sessions during the conference. USAID RDMA Animal Health Advisor, Dr. Sudarat Damrongwatanapokin, will be a panelist on Nov. 3 for a session about the future of One Health. Look on this site for more information about the event after it concludes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening West Africa Collaboration for Epidemic Emergency Rapid Response</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/strengthening-west-africa-collaboration-for-epidemic-emergency-rapid-response</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 13:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/strengthening-west-africa-collaboration-for-epidemic-emergency-rapid-response</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of the efforts to strengthen national and regional mechanisms for surveillance, early warning, preparedness and response to epidemics in West Africa, the West African Health Organization (WAHO), the health arm of the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS), decided to establish an ECOWAS Regional Rapid Response Team (ERRRT) as one of the main components of the new ECOWAS Regional Centre for Disease Surveillance and Control (ECOWAS/RCDC). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P&amp;amp;R provided an important technical and facilitation support to WAHO to prepare and organize an ERRRT Team Building Workshop September 19-23, 2016 in Accra, Ghana. More than 100 delegates from 15 countries reviewed and developed a consensus on the ERRRT composition, terms of references, standard operating procedures, and resources needed during pre-deployment, deployment and recovery phases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a core element of the workshop, P&amp;amp;R designed and facilitated a tabletop simulation exercise of a regional cross-border response to a zoonotic disease outbreak and provided guidance on ways to integrate the One Health approach throughout the process of designing and implementing a regional mechanism for the prevention, detection and response to a public health event of importance to ECOWAS member states. ECOWAS/WAHO leadership, delegates and USAID regional mission commended P&amp;amp;R’s support.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning for Advocacy and Communications in Cameroon</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/planning-for-advocacy-and-communications-in-cameroon</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 13:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/planning-for-advocacy-and-communications-in-cameroon</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the government of Cameroon adopted a national One Health strategy and a national program for prevention and fight emerging and re-emerging zoonotic diseases in 2012, competing priorities and staff turnover have raised the need for continued One Health advocacy and communication efforts, especially leveraging Cameroon’s private sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, with technical support from P&amp;amp;R, the Zoonotic Program facilitated a One Health advocacy and communication action plan development workshop in August 2016. Using the participatory approach, workshop attendees prioritized action plan objectives and defined activities and an implementation timeframe. Participants defined the top four objectives as: 1) integrate One Health approach into training curricula, 2) revise the existing One Health strategy, 3) establish a One Health platform involving the private sector and civil society and 4) develop One Health sectoral briefs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants included representatives from the Prime Minister’s Office and Ministries of Public Health; Higher Education; Forestry and Wildlife; Environment, Natural Conservation and Sustainable Development; Livestock, Fisheries and Animal Industries; Communication; Scientific Research and Innovation; and Territorial Administration. Representatives from the Cameroon Inter-professional Business Group, Exxon Mobil-Cameroon Oil Transport Company, the veterinary national association, UNICEF, FAO-ECTAD, the PREDICT-2 project, and OHCEA/University of Montagne also participated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working Together to Develop One Health in Africa</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/working-together-to-work-together</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 18:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/working-together-to-work-together</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A One Health approach necessitates working across disciplines and across sectors of government. It involves bringing people together—physically or virtually—to share information, collaborate on planning, and coordinate decision-making. The challenge is how to do this as efficiently and cost-effectively as possible. To meet this challenge, P&amp;amp;R launched the Facilitation Capacity Building Initiative. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As P&amp;amp;R began working with countries in Africa and Asia on One Health approaches, the project recognized the need for trained, local facilitators to bring together government officials, civil society organization and members of the private sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Facilitation Capacity Building Initiative was designed to support regional facilitators in strengthening their skills and facilitating the development of One Health approaches. Two six-day training sessions were held, the first in Kampala, Uganda and the second in Abidjan, Cote d’Ivoire. In total, 31 participants were trained in topics like core facilitation skills, decision-making strategies and emotional intelligence. They represented 15 different countries and a wide breadth of experiences, which led to further enrichment beyond what was offered in the course. Over two-thirds of participants were female and over a third were bilingual English-French speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P&amp;amp;R has already begun engagement with East Africa participants for projects in Tanzania, and is expected to roll out additional activities in both regions that will tap into this valuable network of skilled facilitators. The participants expand the pool of resources available not only to support implementation of a One Health approach, but also to increase local capacity for facilitation throughout the region.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving One Health Forward in Bangladesh</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/one-health-operational-guidelines-in-bangladesh</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 15:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/one-health-operational-guidelines-in-bangladesh</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This April, P&amp;amp;R, in collaboration with One Health Bangladesh and Institute of Epidemiology, Disease Control and Research (IEDCR), held a consultative workshop on the operational aspects of One Health institutionalization in Bangladesh. The workshop included 33 participants from government agencies in health, livestock, and environment, as well as other development partners such as USAID, CDC, WHO, FAO and PREDICT-2. Together, they clarified the objectives and process of institutionalizing OH and brainstormed on the nature, composition, staffing, financing, and legal framework of the One Health secretariat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first part of the workshop, two speakers provided the goals and overview of One Health movement. Dr. Mahmudur Rahman, IEDCR Director, presented the evolution, importance and progress of the movement in the country. He also highlighted the need for the institutionalization of One Health to ensure sustainability. Meanwhile, Dr. Nitish Debnath, One Health Coordinator for FAO Bangladesh, provided an overview of the Strategic Framework, with a focus on institutionalization and governance. He emphasized the need for the strategy to be realized, given the ever increasing threats of emerging infectious and zoonotic disease, as well as in capitalizing new developments and opportunities such as GHSA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/bangladesh_operations.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bangladesh_operations&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop participants discuss secretariat structure.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P&amp;amp;R Director Jerry Martin also clarified what what the project can do to assist the countries by adapting to their needs and challenges. Together with Dr. Pasakorn Akarasewi, the P&amp;amp;R Southeast Asia Regional Director, they shared experiences in working and supporting One Health in the countries of Kenya and Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking out into three groups, participants were tasked with outlining secretariat: functions, staffing and line of command; funding arrangements; location; legal framework; and the composition of the expert advisory group. The enthusiastic and lively discussions within the groups generated lots of ideas and recommendations regarding the questions posed to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outputs, ideas and recommendations of the workshop will be incorporated into the working papers for the May 2016 inter-ministerial meeting to develop the secretariat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Animal and Human Health Surveillance in Liberia</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/animal-and-human-health-surveillance-in-liberia</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 19:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/animal-and-human-health-surveillance-in-liberia</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The World Bank will be providing the Government of Liberia with a $30 million line of credit through REDISSE to support animal and human health surveillance, preparedness and response, and laboratory capacity.  At the REDISSE Workshop, P&amp;amp;R, in conjunction with PREDICT2, ensured that wildlife and animal health were considered in the planning for new national surveillance systems and that animal health and wildlife professionals would be included as part of Rapid Response Teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P&amp;amp;R worked with Liberia’s Forest Development Authority (FDA), which oversees wildlife, to participate in REDISSE planning at the suggestion of the ministries of Health and Agriculture. P&amp;amp;R also conducted a strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, and threats analysis for the REDISSE proposal to identify surveillance and preparedness gaps and suggest surveillance systems that could be used within the FDA system. P&amp;amp;R also assisted Ministry of Agriculture in identifying its priorities within the available REDISSE funding and develop a one-year work plan. P&amp;amp;R facilitated meetings with the ministries of Health, Agriculture and others to reduce cost and realize efficiencies in integrating animal health surveillance and laboratory data into a human health information platform currently being piloted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, Liberia is a country with significant needs. The ministries of Agriculture and Health and the Forestry Development Authority have expressed their commitment to One Health; however, at this time, Agriculture and Forestry cannot act as equal partners to the Ministry of Health as neither organization has the data, trained personnel, or logistical resources to contribute to One Health collaborative activities. On the other hand, multiple funding sources are supporting Ministry of Health’s health systems strengthening including in surveillance, laboratory capacity, and preparedness and response. Agriculture and Forestry need substantial investments to build their systems and their capabilities to prepare for outbreak events, prevent on-going animal health issues, provide accurate and timely surveillance data, and respond to events once they occur.  With respect to animal health issues, each organization is under resourced and lack capacity.  Specifically, neither has an active surveillance system, a fully operational veterinary laboratory, and the capacity to readily respond to an outbreak.  In addition, they lack animal health personnel; there is only one veterinarian at the Ministry of Agriculture and none at the FDA. In the coming months, P&amp;amp;R will work with the Government of Liberia to establish a One Health Steering Committee and support the inclusion of One Health in other existing initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Policy and Advocacy Strategy in Kenya</title>
      <link>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/building-a-policy-and-advocacy-strategy-in-kenya</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 19:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Preparedness and Response Staff</author>
      <guid>http://preparednessandresponse.org/news/building-a-policy-and-advocacy-strategy-in-kenya</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2006-2007, an outbreak of Rift Valley fever in East Africa killed approximately 500 people and infected more than 200,000. In Kenya alone, the outbreak cost $32 million in livestock losses and international export bans, according to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration. Now, another outbreak appears possible this year due to extreme rainfall from El Niño.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outbreak prompted Kenya to organize national assets against future epidemics. With assistance from the CDC and USAID’s Emerging Pandemic Threats program, the country established a One Health platform—the Zoonotic Disease Unit (ZDU). While the platform enjoyed broad acceptance, the group was provided little funding and authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, with assistance from P&amp;amp;R, the ZDU is actively building its capacity and its case for legislative support and funding. On March 2-3, P&amp;amp;R technical specialists organized and conducted a policy advocacy and communication workshop in Nairobi. Twenty-nine participants from ministries and partner organizations met under the leadership of the ZDU to draft an advocacy strategy and action plan. These same stakeholders met March 14–15, with P&amp;amp;R leading another workshop to develop the ZDU’s preparedness and response plan to a public health emergency of initially unknown etiology. In May, the ZDU will present a final advocacy strategy and action plan to the Zoonotic Technical Working Group (ZTWG), the ZDU’s steering committee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With assistance from P&amp;amp;R, the ZDU will deliver advocacy and messaging to senior government officials and the private sector later this year, so these key decision makers fully understand the necessity of the One Health approach in Kenya. The goal of the advocacy strategy is that, with this increased understanding, decision makers and the private sector will be willing to provide additional financial, technical, and/ or human resources to the One Health Platform. This will not only strengthen the platform’s efforts to better detect and respond to emerging pandemics, but also increase its domestic financing, helping make the platform more sustainable and less reliant on donor funding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
